

Phone +919726047465

Email

miteshbhoi@gmail.com

Location Anand, India

About me

I am a dedicated HTML Email Template Developer specializing in creating responsive HTML email templates with over 5 years of experience with hopes of advancing my career as an Email Marketing Specialist.

Furthermore, I have over 10 years of experience as a professional front-end developer specializing in developing fully responsive HTML pages using HTML, CSS, jQuery, and Bootstrap.

I am fluent in HTML, and CSS, and have intermediate knowledge in JS. My software abilities are fluent in Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD, Figma, and Invision, so for any projects require a person with a creative flair and the technical ability to bring your ideas to life then please get in touch.

I have a high level of visual accuracy and speed without compromising in other areas.

Experience

HTML Email Template Developer / PSD to HTML Developer / Bootstrap Developer, Upwork

2016 - Present | Anand, India

- Implemented procedures for testing and troubleshooting of HTML and revised code.
- Formulated procedures for slicing and optimizing images for Landing pages and HTML Emails utilizing Photoshop.
- Assisted in hand-coding and implementation of Landing pages and HTML emails through Dreamweaver and also using Visual Studio.
- Producing, maintaining, and modifying websites and user interfaces.
- Ensuring websites are accessible across many platforms, including laptops and smartphones.
- Ensuring HTML pages and HTML Email templates are accessible across different web browsers and email clients.
- Ability to test and debug websites.

HTML Email Template Developer, S'well Bottle

2018 - 2021 | Anand, India

- Hand-coded/implemented HTML emails and innovative landing pages using clean, standards-compliant code in Dreamweaver.
- Tested and troubleshot HTML, and revised code when necessary to ensure campaigns were rendered properly across multiple email clients, browsers, and mobile devices.
- Sliced and optimized images for HTML emails using Photoshop.
- QA the day-to-day email campaigns using Litmus and Email on Acid.
- Ability to complete tasks independently, and as part of a team.

- Optimizing the user experience.
- Using HTML, JavaScript, and CSS to bring concepts to life.
- Developing and maintaining the user interface.
- Implementing design on mobile websites.
- Creating tools that improve site interaction regardless of the browser.
- Managing software workflow.
- Following SEO best practices.
- Fixing bugs and testing for usability.

Frontend Developer, CCube Interfaces Pvt. Ltd.

2008 - 2013 | Anand, India

- Responsible for developing and designing many unique and comprehensive websites using Dreamweaver.
- Hand-coded XHTML and CSS (compatible with standards-compliant browsers).
- Included JavaScript (jQuery) Libraries to enhance web pages, provide dynamic functionality, keep the code base light and reduce server load.
- Debugged issues discovered while testing, tested the site for cross-browser compatibility (IE, Firefox, Chrome, Safari).
- Used FileZilla to FTP web sites.

Education

Sardar Patel University

Master in Computer Application, Masters

2005 - 2008 | Anand, India

Sardar Patel University

Bachelor in Mathematics, Bachelor

2001 - 2004 | Anand, India

Skills

E-mail | JavaScript | Landing Pages | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe Dreamweaver | E-mail | Bootstrap | jQuery | CSS | HTML

Languages

English (Intermediate) Hindi (Native) Gujarati (Native)